Ivo Gatzinski

Profile

College instructor, interdisciplinary tutor, holistic mentor, and student-centered teacher with seventeen years of experience in dynamic and responsive learning environments. Collaborative, attentive, and compassionate listener that meets concrete needs of diverse students. Proficient with online/hybrid instruction on several online learning platforms, including Blackboard, eCollege, Canvas. Software skills, incl. SARS' TheGrid, DataTel, MSOffice, Google Apps. Sensitive to others' perspectives, having lived in six countries on four continents. Fluent in Bulgarian & Russian; moderately competent in French; basic skills in Japanese.

Competencies

- Social Sciences & Humanities
- Active Learning Methods
- Individual & Group Tutoring

- Interdisciplinary Learning
- ESL & Remedial Strategies
- Adult & Veteran Learners

Teaching Experience

Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

Miramar College Department of Political Science, San Diego, CA

2019-Present

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively

Adjunct Faculty in Economics

Southwestern College Department of Economics, Chula Vista, CA

2016-2017

Taught economics, and relevant social science research, academic writing, reading, and math skills

Tutor in Social Sciences, Humanities, and ESL

Grossmont College Tutoring Center, El Cajon, CA

2013-2016

- Coached diverse students in economics, sociology, political science, history, research, and writing
- Responded with sensitivity and compassion to coordinate accessibility accommodations
- Taught interdisciplinary material clearly and accessibly to diverse learners and audiences
- Collaborated with staff and faculty to design and administer tutoring services and workshops

Southwestern College Academic Success Center, Chula Vista, CA

2016

Tutored diverse ESL students in academic writing, English, social sciences, and basic math skills

Adjunct Faculty in Political Science

Grossmont College Department of Political Economy

2013-2016

- Taught U.S. government, introductory and comparative politics, theory, economics, social science research, and academic writing via individual tutoring, on-site, hybrid, and online instruction, using various online learning platforms, such as Blackboard, Canvas, Aplia, Connect, etc.
- Tutored diverse students to enable holistic growth in learning capacities
- Constructed and applied criteria to measure, assess, monitor, and report student learning outcomes
- Engaged diverse learners and audiences by translating complex ideas and academic research clearly and accessibly into ordinary language in lectures, seminars, and workshops
- Designed active learning strategies for investigating politics and society objectively
- Resolved misinterpretations, complaints, conflicts, and cultural frictions between diverse students, responding with sensitivity and compassion to complex needs

Adjunct Faculty in Sociology & Political Science

National University 2013-2017

- Taught sociology of gender, race, class, economics, and family; social theory; introduction to sociology; introduction to politics, comparative politics, U.S. government; social science research design, on-site, hybrid, and online, with variety of learning platforms, e.g. Blackboard, eCollege, Canvas, etc.
- Met unique needs of working adult veterans from complex and diverse backgrounds
- Mediated verbal and body-language misunderstandings from diverse student viewpoints

Ivo Gatzinski

- Clearly explicated complex material for working adults in highly accelerated, intensive curriculum
- Facilitated respectful, fluid discussions for the scientific study of sensitive political and social topics
- Compiled and used various criteria, databases, platforms to measure and evaluate learning outcomes

Teaching Assistant

Roosevelt College MMW Writing Curriculum, UC San Diego

2007-2015

- Taught academic writing, scholarly research, humanities, and social sciences to undergraduates via individual and group workshops, seminars, and hybrid instruction with various learning platforms
- Trained students in all aspects of scholarly research and academic writing, attending carefully to diverse needs to enable growth of learning capacities, writing skills, and critical thinking
- Diagnosed student needs to design active learning strategies for individual tutoring and seminars
- Collaborated closely with diverse team to evaluate and improve procedures and criteria for teaching, tutoring, and program services, for a multi-cultural, liberal arts curriculum in world civilizations
- Met unique needs of students from diverse linguistic, cultural, academic, and personal backgrounds, including English language learners and students transferring from community colleges
- Created, evaluated, enhanced, and implemented precise, highly structured writing assignments
- Constructed and evaluated criteria for measuring and assessing student learning outcomes

Teaching Assistant

Department of Political Science, UC San Diego

2003-2007

- Taught comparative politics and theory, history, religion, urban development, ethics, and sociology
- Trained wide range of students in plural scientific methodologies for interdisciplinary research design
- Diagnosed student needs to accurately customize interactive learning strategies in social sciences
- Distilled and translated political science and sociology into ordinary language for diverse audiences

Education

Ph.D. Candidate Political Science, UC San Diego M.A. Political Science, UC San Diego	2003-2012 2005
B.A. Economics, Amherst College, Magna Cum Laude, Phi Beta Kappa	2002
Relevant Professional Development	
Minority Male Community College Collaborative, San Diego State University Learned institutional practices to improve outcomes for men of color in community college	2014-2016
Accessibility Workshop, Grossmont Community College Learned techniques and legal principles for creating accessible multimedia materials	2015
 QPR Gatekeeper Training, Grossmont Community College Learned how to recognize the warning signs of a suicide crisis Practiced how to question, persuade and refer to further help 	2015
Race in Education Workshop, Grossmont Community College Studied the pedagogic value in acknowledging individual and contextual differences	2015
 CCC Professional Development Program, Grossmont Community College Practiced how to help a student struggling with psychological distress Strategized how to create a supportive environment for student veterans Trained how to create a supportive environment for LGBTQ students 	2014
 CIRTL University Teaching Certificate, UCSD Center for Teaching Development Collaborated in practicing teaching standards developed by the national CIRTL Network Evaluated teaching experience in a self-consciously scientific and collaborative way 	2012
Conference Participation (WPSA, MPSA, APT, SWPSA) • Elucidated Rousseau & Wittgenstein's critique of sovereign justification in social contract theory	2009-2013